我们，是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文！
and Steven!
友谊的飞船
翻译
零九/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
愚蠢破烂损坏传送台
Stupid broken warp.
先是通讯中枢
First the communication hub.
现在这个又被破坏了
Now this is busted again.
这群水晶战士还真是个威胁
These crystal gems are a menace.
哦，啊哈！看！我是对的！
Oh, aha! Look! I was right!
我的计划实现的非常完美
My plan worked perfectly.
早上好
Good morning.
还是没忘记Uncle Grandpa的话啊
搞毛？
What?
你们怎么知道我在这？
How did you know I was here?
我-们找到了一个跟踪你的秘密方法
We found a secret way to track you
而且就算你诚心诚意的问了我们也不告诉你
and we'll never tell you how even if you ask nicely.
Nyeh!
橄榄石！我们来这里是-
Peridot! We're here to --
而且你永远也逃不掉的！
and you'll never get away with this!
你们几个 宝石人除了干扰我就没别的事可做？
Don't you gems have anything better to do than annoy me?
当然，我们要-
Nope. We're gonna --
准备好恼火吧
prepare to be annoyed.
我没时间搞这个
I don't have time for this!
这个星球有个死期
This planet has an expiration date,
洛克人的标志性手炮？
而我可不想呆在这搞清是什么时候！
and I'm not gonna stick around to find out when!
蛤？
Wha?
呃...
Uh...
够了！我要搞定她
That's it. I'm taking her out.
珍珠，等等！
Pearl, wait!
橄榄石使用的技能与《超能陆战队中》中的“超劲先生”类似——都是用某种场将目标困住；
且二者都喜欢将目标玩弄一番
哈！
Ha!
对不起，但你走错方-向-了！
Sorry. But you're going the wrong way!
抓住她！
Get her!
你没打中哦
You missed.
珍珠！
Pearl!
呃？
Huh?
啊～这个破烂星球就没一个正常工作的东西吗？
Ah, doesn't anything work on this cruddy planet?
我就行！
I do!
蛤？
Huh?
嗷～！
Ow!
紫晶，接住！
Amethyst, catch!
搞破坏！
Destroy!
啊～！
Aah!
我能抓住她！我能抓住她！我能抓住她！
I got her! I got her! I got her!
珍珠！
Pearl!
噢，赶紧起来！
Oh, get off me!
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起，对不～对不～对不～对不~对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
哇，这可真是尴尬啊
Wow. This is just sad.
我几乎为你们感到抱歉了
I almost feel sorry for you.
Nyeh!
周末愉快！
Have a great weekend.
我是指，我，希望，她的周末，不怎么，愉快？
I mean, I hope her weekend is not so great.
好吧，我有意识到了刚才算是惨败
Okay, I realize that was a bit of a fiasco.
但还是有点收获的！
But there's a silver lining to this.
现在我们确定我们能追踪她的所有动向！
Now we know for sure that we can track her every movement.
每当她使用传送系统时
Whenever she uses the warp system,
她的逃生舱会立刻探测到她在哪里
her escape pod will instantly detect exactly where she is.
我们抓到她只是个时间问题，
It's only a matter of time until we catch her,
而且当我们做到时，我们就能放下之前的问题，
and when we do, we'll be able to close this chapter
并最终再次前进，对吧？
and finally move on, right?
有没有什么可能是你们两个
Isn't there something that maybe the two of you
也许要谈谈的？
might need to talk about?
是橄榄石
It's Peridot.
她现在就在使用传送台
She's using the warps right now.
看，她就在这里
Look. This is where she is.
这次我们肯定能抓住她了
We got her for sure this time.
如果她认为她是占上风的话，
If she thinks she's got the upper hand,
那么她又有麻烦了——我们
then she has another thing coming, and that's us.
呃，至少珍珠还很乐观
Well, at least Pearl's optimistic.
这没用
It won't help.
她尽可以献上橄榄石，
She could hand Peridot over on a silver platter,
但这并不能弥补她为了和
but it won't make up for the stunt she pulled
石榴融合而编织的骗局
to get Garnet to fuse with her.
史蒂文，咱们走！
Steven, let's go.
喔
Whoa.
哈！她太过绝望了
Ha! She's desperate.
看看！她把自己困在了那里
Look at this. She's cornered herself in there.
Hmm.
我们刚好让她到了我们想要的地方
We've got her just where we want her.
这是-
What is --
好问题，史蒂文
excellent question, Steven.
我们现在看到的
What we see before us
是个原始的星际宝石飞船
is an ancient interplanetary gem vessel.
母世界的宝石人们通过这些飞船穿越太空
Homeworld gems used these ships to travel across the cosmos
来到地球-这当然是在传送台建成之前
and land here on earth before the warp pads were built.
但这些飞船在这里待了太长时间了
But these ships landed here so long ago
不可能还可以正常工作
that there's no way they can be functional.
橄榄石没什么选择余地了
Peridot's running out of options.
珍珠，我们可不能浪费时间
Pearl, we can't waste time.
让我们专注于任务-
Let's focus on the task at --
啊，对，手头的任务
ah, yes. The task at hand.
不能瞎聊了，让我们一起抓橄榄石吧！
No more doddling. Let's go get Peridot!
这看起来更像是个温室，而非太空飞船
It's more like a greenhouse than a spaceship.
看来地球赢得了这场斗争
Looks like earth won this battle.
哦
Oh.
你们这些宝石人真是比渣土还蠢
You gems really are as dull as dirt.
你才是蠢货，如果你觉得你能飞的了这破烂的话
You're the dull one if you think you can fly this wreck.
啊？你说话能大声点吗？
What? Can you speak louder?
有的通讯器报销了
Some of these communicators are gunked up.
珍珠说，你才是蠢货
Pearl says you're the dull one
如果你认为你能飞的了这破烂
if you think you can fly this wreck.
飞？
Fly?
我可不是要飞这艘飞船
I'm not using this vessel to fly.
我是用它来困住你们的！
I'm using it to trap you!
这很好吧？
Isn't this nice?
不再有水晶战士四处乱跑
No more crystal gems running around,
打乱我的计划，破坏我的物品
messing with my plans, destroying my things.
看来我刚好让你们出现在我想要的位置
Looks like I've got you just where I want you.
感觉怎么样，如此轻易的被算计，你们这群草包？！
How does it feel to be so easily outsmarted, you clods?!
不
No.
嘿，呃...我是紫晶
Hey, uh... This is Amethyst.
我可不喜欢被叫做草包，你个草-
I don't appreciate being called a clod, you clo--
说够了
enough talk.
准备好迎接毁灭吧！
Prepare yourselves for annihilation!
Hyah!
Hyah.
啊！这个还能用
Aha! It works.
好！
Yes!
去死死死死死死死死死死死死吧！
Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die! Die~!
像不像美国队长？
嘿，伙计们，这里
Hey, guys, over here.
这个方向
This way.
你真是太屌了，史蒂文！
You're on fire, Steven!
那可是一天内三个盾啊
That's three shields in one day.
可不算差了！
Not too shabby!
快走！
Move!
尖刺！你们喜欢我的尖刺吗？！
Spikes! How do you like my spikes?!
橄榄石！
Peridot!
珍珠，不要-
Pearl, don't just --
你个笨蛋
You idiot.
啊！呀！呀！呀！
Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah!
珍珠，停下，这没有用
Pearl, stop. That isn't helping.
我总得做点什么吧？
I have to do something.
我不敢相信我直接将我们带进了橄榄石的陷阱
I can't believe I walked us right into Peridot's trap.
这都是我的...错误？
This is all my...Fault?
Huh?
啊～～～～～～！
Aah!
呃？
Huh?
我抓住你了，史蒂文
I got you, Steven.
谢谢，紫晶
Thanks, Amethyst.
石榴和珍珠
Garnet and Pearl.
你们还好吗？
Are you guys okay?
我们很好
We're fine.
遭了
Crud.
我们得救她们出来！
We've got to get them out.
紫晶，我们该怎么-
Amethyst, what should we --
石榴，我对不起
Pearl: Garnet, I'm sorry.
等下
Wait a sec.
事情本不应变成这样的
Things weren't supposed to turn out this way.
我们总能离开的
We'll get out of here somehow.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I mean.
我非常想抓住橄榄石，以弥补我犯下的错误
I really wanted to catch Peridot to make up for what I did.
我想向你证明-
I wanted to prove to you that --
一切都能变回正常的样子
that everything could go back to normal.
抓住橄榄石并不能让一切回归正常
Catching Peridot won't make things go back to normal.
这和橄榄石无关
This isn't about Peridot.
嘿！她们开始相互说话了
Hey, they're actually talking.
现在她们总算能解决问题了
Now they can finally work things out.
除非她们被压碎！
Not if they get crushed!
请告诉我！
Please tell me!
我怎样才能让你原谅我？
How can I make you forgive me?!
无论如何都不能！你欺骗了我
You can't. You lied to me.
你必须认识到你的所作所为会有后果的
You need to learn that there are consequences to your actions.
我对不起，我...我不能控制住自己
I'm sorry. I...I couldn't help myself.
我不想听你的借口！
I don't want to hear your excuses.
但这是真的
But it's true.
不论我如何尝试像你一样强大
No matter how hard I try to be strong like you,
我仍只是个珍珠
I'm just a Pearl.
我独自一人时一无是处
I'm useless on my own.
我需要有人告诉我做什么
I need someone to tell me what to do.
当我们融合时，我能体会到作为你的感觉
When we fuse, I can feel what it's like to be you.
自信，有安全感，充实
Confident and secure and complete.
你是如此完美
You're perfect.
你是一个完美的关系
You're the perfect relationship.
你们总是在一起
You're always together.
我只是-我想成为其中的一部分
I just -- I wanted to be a part of that.
你错了
You're wrong.
我没你想的那么强大
I'm not as strong as you think.
我-我因为这件事破裂了
I-I fell apart over this.
红宝石和蓝宝石因为你蒙骗我吵得不可开交
Ruby and Sapphire were in turmoil over how you deceived me.
我瓦解了
I came undone.
喔，那真的发生了？
Whoa. That really happened?
嗯
Hmm.
掌控一切并不容易
It's not easy being in control.
我也有弱点
I have weaknesses, too,
但我选择不让弱点占上风
but I choose not to let them consume me.
我努力保持强大
I struggle to stay strong
因为我知道我对其他人的巨大影响力
because I know the impact I have on everyone.
一定要明白，珍珠，你也有影响力
Please understand, Pearl, you have an impact, too.
很多次我都将你视为力量的象征
There are times when I look up to you for strength.
你是为你自己而存在的宝石人
You are your own gem.
你控制着自己的命运
You control your destiny.
而不是我，或者玫瑰，或者史蒂文
Not me, not Rose, not Steven.
但你必须选择变得强大，然后我们才能前行，
But you must choose to be strong so we can move forward,
然后我才能再次信任你
so I can trust you again.
我理解了，我不能再自暴自弃了
I understand. I can't give up anymore.
很好
Good.
珍珠，现在只有一个方法能解决问题
Pearl, there's only one way out of this.
只要你愿意的话
Only if you're okay with it.
嗯
Mm.
啊！
Aah!
怎么办？怎么办？怎么办？怎么办？
What do we do?! What do we do?! What do we do?! What do we do?!
红玛瑙手中的钻头与《天元突破-红莲螺岩》中的钻头武器类似
这个垃圾按钮
Stupid button here.
我不知道还有什么-啊～！
I don't know what anything is -- aah!
炸了这堆宝石古董！
Blast this old gem tech!
她们去哪了？为什么没东西能工作？！
Where did they go? Why isn't anything working?!
啊～！
Aah!
投降吧，橄榄石
Surrender, Peridot.
你无处可逃了
You have nowhere to run.
水晶战士-要抓住你了！
The Crystal Gems are gonna get you.
你们真以为就结束了？
You really think this is the end?
这-这才只是开端...
This -- this is only the beginning...
我跑路的开端
Of my escape.
其实，我很想留下来
Well, I'd love to stick around
观看你们另一次可悲的抓捕我的无用功
and watch another one of your pathetic attempts to capture me,
但我想我实在太聪明了
but I guess I'm just too smart
相比于你们这群愚蠢臃肿的草包！
for the likes of you lumpy, clumpy clods.
搞毛？
What the?
我抓到只橄榄石哦
I caught a Peridot.
"I caught a ***"，像不像口袋妖怪？
嘿！将你的触碰肢从我身上拿开，你个史蒂文
Hey, get your touch stumps off me, you Steven.
嘿！
Hey!
坚持住，史蒂文！
Yeah, Steven!
别放走她
Don't let her go.
放开我！
Let go of me!
你-你个顽固，矮挫的鬼东西
You -- you persistent, little whatever exactly you are!
橄榄石，你的航班，被取消了！
Peridot, your flight's been canceled.
不~！
No!
橄榄石断脚的镜头可能是受1983年的电视剧《G型神探》中克劳博士和《大怪兽空中战》(Gamera vs. Gyaos)的启发
你们会付出代价的，水晶战士
You'll pay for this, crystal gems.
我迟早会报复的
I'll get you back.
你们给我等着～！
Just you wa-a-a-it!
珍珠？
Pearl?
这不算什么，史蒂文
It's okay, Steven.
下次，我们就能抓到她生下的部分了
Next time, we'll get the rest of her.
对吧，石榴？
Right, Garnet?
这是坚实的一步
It's a good step forward.
脚的段子！
Foot joke!
总算结束了
Finally.
你
♪ You
爱，如你
♪ love like you